# JINGWEI ZUO

- ★ Versailles, France
- **J** (+33) (0)6 50 13 98 29
- @ jingwei.zuo.career@gmail.com

Ph.D. in Machine Learning

jingweizuo.com in linkedin.com/in/jingweizuo github.com/JingweiZuo





Oct. 2018 - May 2022

As a new-graduate PhD in computer science with hands-on experience in machine (deep) learning, time series analysis and data science ecosystems, I am open to Data Scientist, Machine Learning Engineer and Machine Learning Researcher roles.

### **EDUCATION**

_	· ···· · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · ·	000. 2010 May 2022
•	Université Paris-Saclay, advisors: Prof. Karine Zeitouni, Dr. Yehia Taher	Versailles, France
	o Thesis: Representation Learning and Forecasting for Inter-related Time Series	
•	Master in Data Science, graduated with highest honors	Sept. 2017 - Sept. 2018
	Université Paris-Saclay	Versailles, France
•	Engineer in Computer Science	Sept. 2014 - Aug. 2017
	Polytech Sorbonne - Sorbonne Université	Paris, France
•	Bachelor of Science in Optical and Electronic Information	Sept. 2011 - Aug. 2014
	Huazhong University of Science and Technology (HUST)	Wuhan, China

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

•	Teaching Assistant - UVSQ, Université Paris-Saclay	Sept. 2019 - Sept. 2021
	Giving undergraduate/graduate-level courses on Data Mining, Software Engineering, etc.	Versailles, France

#### Research Intern, DAVID Lab - UVSQ, Université Paris-Saclay Apr. 2018 - Sept. 2018 Topic: "Big Time Series Classification \( \bar{Q} \)" Versailles. France

- o Utilized Python and Scala to implement supervised machine learning algorithms for time series activity recognition on real artwork transportation data, which is validated by our collaborators in C2RMF.
- o Proposed a distributed algorithm on **Spark** for time series classification, which reduced total processing time by 75% in local Docker cluster, by 99% in AWS EMR cluster with 30 distributed nodes.
- o Publication: J. Zuo, K. Zeitouni and Y. Taher. Exploring Interpretable Features for Large Time Series with SE4TeC, demo, International Conference on Extending Database Technology (EDBT 2019), CORE ranking: A

# Part-time R&D Intern, PETRUS Team - Inria Saclay

Dec. 2017 - Mar. 2018

Topic: "Mobile Personal Medical Folder on PlugDB"

Versailles. France

- o Utilized Java (Android) and SQL to implement a mobile personal medical folder on a secure personal database (PlugDB).
- o This project is set to be deployed in the Central Hospital of Yaoundé for over 1000 tracked patients with diabetes.

# Software Engineer Intern, Orange Labs

Mar. 2017 - Aug. 2017

Topic: "Authentication Technologies on IoT devices"

Lannion, France

• Utilized C and C# to implement authentication technologies on IoT devices.

# **SKILLS**

- Programming Languages: Python, Java, Scala, C, C++, C#, R, JavaScript, SQL, Matlab
- Big Data & Machine Learning: Spark, Hadoop, Kafka, Redis, InfluxDB, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, ElasticSearch, Kibana, Grafana; scikit-learn, Tensorflow, Keras, PyTorch
- Miscellaneous Technologies: A/B testing, ETL, Data science pipeline (cleansing, wrangling, visualization, modeling, interpretation), Statistics, Experimental design, Hypothesis testing, Git, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS
- Languages: Chinese (Native); French, English (Fluent).

- Supervised Learning on Time Series Stream Q: Dynamic Representation Learning for Classification
  - Utilized **Python** and **Flask** to implement scalable algorithms and a visualization web application for dynamic representation learning from time series stream.
  - o Achieved the best classification results on 12 UCR time series datasets and saved up to 96% of processing time.
  - <u>Publication</u>: J. Zuo et al., Incremental and Adaptive Feature Exploration over Time Series Stream. IEEE International Conference on Big Data (IEEE BigData 2019), acceptance rate: 19%
  - <u>Publication</u>: J. Zuo et al., ISETS: Incremental Shapelet Extraction from Time Series Stream, demo, ECML-PKDD'19, CORE ranking: A
- **Streamer**  Open-Source Framework for Continuous Learning in Data Streams
  - Utilized **Java** to integrate the time series stream algorithms into a practical data stream learning pipeline: data stream ingestion (Kafka), data storage (InfluxDB), model storage (Redis) and visualisation (Kibana).
  - o Enriched the functionalities of Streamer with our collaborators in CEA-List.
- Semi-supervised Learning on Time Series (7): Interpretable Representation Learning
  - Utilized Keras to implement an autoencoder-based model, which tackles the label shortage problem in multivariate time series learning.
  - Achieved the best accuracy over the state-of-the-art approaches on the UEA Archive containing 30 multivariate time series datasets, while guaranteeing the model's interpretability.
  - Publication: J. Zuo et al., SMATE: Semi-supervised Spatio-Temporal Representation Learning on Multivariate Time Series, IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM 2021), CORE ranking: A\*
- Traffic Forecasting: Incomplete Time Series Forecasting with Graph Neural Networks
  - Utilized PyTorch on IDRIS GPU cluster to test and implement time series forecasting models for real-life traffic data, which contains over 16 million observations with complex missing values.
  - o Achieved better predictions than both the statistic models (e.g., ARIMA) and recent deep learning approaches.
  - <u>Publication</u>: J. Zuo et al., Graph Convolutional Networks for Traffic Forecasting with Missing Values. under review by DMKD, Springer.
- PolluScope 🚱: Distributed Query, Multi-view Learning, Pollution Activity Recognition, Classification
  - Combined PySpark and Scala-UDF to implement distributed query operators on multi-granular time series database, which reduced the query's time by 90% compared to PySpark.
  - Utilized Python and scikit-learn to implement a multi-view learning model from the multi-source time series, which
    improved the accuracy by 9% over single-view learners on the actual pollution exposure data collected in Île-de-France.
  - <u>Publication</u>: H. El Hafyani, M. Abboud, **J. Zuo**, et al., Learning the Micro-environment from Rich Trajectories in the context of Mobile Crowd Sensing Application to Air Quality Monitoring, under review by Geoinformatica, Springer
  - <u>Publication</u>: H. El Hafyani, M. Abboud, **J. Zuo** et al., Tell Me What Air You Breathe, I Tell You Where You Are, demo, International Symposium on Spatial and Temporal Databases (SSTD 2021)
  - Publication: M. Abboud, H. El Hafyani, J. Zuo et al., Micro-environment Recognition in the context of Environmental Crowdsensing, 4th workshop on Big Mobility Data Analytics (BMDA@EDBT 2021)

# **COURSEWORK**

- **Graduate**: Data Science (Database, Data Integration, Data Mining, Machine learning, Cloud Computing), Programming (Java, Scala, C++, Software Engineering), Signal Processing, Project Management, Entrepreneurship, etc.
- Undergraduate: Mathematics, Physics, Computer Architecture, Operating Systems, etc.
- 5th Int. winter school on Big Data: one-week training program on Big Data at University of Cambridge
- ullet 3rd  $DS^3$  summer school: one-week training program on Data Science at École Polytechnique
- IA<sup>2</sup> autumn school 2019: one-week training program on Artificial Intelligence at INSA Lyon

#### PROFESSIONAL SERVICES AND AWARDS

- Organizing committee: Web chair of IEEE MDM'20, committee member of JDSE'19
- Program committee: ECML-PKDD'20
- Reviewing activities: AAAI'21, IEEE ICDE'21, SSTD'21, IEEE DSAA'20
- Student travel award & volunteering: IEEE International Conference on Big Data 2019